<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Banks on schmichael&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/banks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Banks on schmichael&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/banks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Banks</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/03/08/bad-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/03/08/bad-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I try to keep up with the news, like most Americans I really have only a vague picture of this financial crisis we&amp;#8217;re in, and how to get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple pieces of media I&amp;#8217;ve found helpful in figuring out whats going on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thisamericanlife.org/Radio_Episode.aspx?episode=375&#34;&gt;This American Life did an excellent episode called Bad Banks&lt;/a&gt; which nicely explains the basic fundamentals of the banking industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week I half jokingly told friends on Thursday I expected to wake up Friday morning to find that the government had taken over the banking system. One of my friends passed on this link to an excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2009/03/06/60minutes/main4848047.shtml&#34;&gt;60 Minutes* piece on what happens when banks fail and are taken over by the FDIC&lt;/a&gt; (short story: &lt;em&gt;[Don&amp;#8217;t Panic][3]&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the best line from either of those pieces is from the This American Life episode when professor David Beim states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is not the banks, greedy though they may be, overpaid though they may be. &lt;strong&gt;The problem is us.&lt;/strong&gt; We have over-borrowed. We have been living very high on the hog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;(emphasis mine)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And now, the rest of the story&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is a blog! I can&amp;#8217;t just post some links without expounding upon my own poorly informed views! I&amp;#8217;m an American dammit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are some of my current thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;m pro stimulus package.&lt;/strong&gt; If there&amp;#8217;s ever a time for deficit spending its when the economy is in trouble and people need jobs. The &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; time for deficit spending is to destroy and then rebuild sovereign nations for no good reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I believe the government should &lt;strong&gt;Take over &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the failed banks&lt;/strong&gt;. These &lt;em&gt;too-big-to-fail&lt;/em&gt; behemoths should be taken over, parceled up, and sold off. Too-big-to-fail is unacceptable. The tax payers would probably end up paying a price for this, but consider it the &lt;strong&gt;War on Bad Banks&lt;/strong&gt;. Over the past 8 years we&amp;#8217;ve paid billions to fight a mostly phony &amp;#8220;War on Terror&amp;#8221;, why not spend billions on something that would have a positive result for humanity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the future we need regulations similar to anti-trust laws to prevent so few corporations from wielding so much power. In the computer world we turn to distributed systems to provide redundancy in case of failure. The non-geeky world has a nice little saying for this: &lt;em&gt;don&amp;#8217;t put all your eggs in one basket.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;* I hadn&amp;#8217;t seen the 60 Minutes in years. The journalist doing the story kind of annoyed me, but overall I thought it addressed something on the minds of many Americans in a very personal way.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i2.photobucket.com/albums/y34/dilliwag/panic.jpg&#34;&gt;http://i2.photobucket.com/albums/y34/dilliwag/panic.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>