<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Atheros on schmichael&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/atheros/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Atheros on schmichael&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/atheros/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New Cable Internet, 22″ LCD, and WiFi!</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2007/12/17/new-cable-internet-22-lcd-and-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2007/12/17/new-cable-internet-22-lcd-and-wifi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was my work Christmas! I work from home most of the time, so I&amp;#8217;m finally getting around to upgrading some of the equipment I use for my job every day. Today I got 3 new pieces of technology and just finished setting them all up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goodbye ATT&amp;amp;T!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched from 1.5 Mbps/386 Kbps DSL to 10 Mbps/1 Mbps cable broadband today. I used to download packages at 140 KBps to 160 KBps, but now I easily reach over 1 MBps. Tomorrow I get to call AT&amp;amp;T and cancel not only my DSL but also my landline phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only downside is starting in 2008, my local cable company, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insight-com.com/&#34;&gt;Insight&lt;/a&gt;, is going to become &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comcast.com/&#34;&gt;Comcast&lt;/a&gt;. It took me about 10 seconds to get a human on the line when calling Insight. When I tried to call Comcast to find out if anything was going to change, I had to call &lt;em&gt;3 different phone numbers&lt;/em&gt; until I finally reached a sales person who kept trying to sell me a package deal for broadband/tv/phone even though Comcast isn&amp;#8217;t in my area yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales representatives for both companies seemed very confused that a person would only want Internet access. My wife &amp;amp; I watch all of our TV online or through Netflix, and we don&amp;#8217;t need a landline phone. Is that really so strange these days? I suppose most people still have cable TV or satellite, but with more shows becoming available for free online I don&amp;#8217;t see the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello 22&amp;#8243; LCD!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got a nice LCD and got rid of my $5 19&amp;#8243; inch CRT (thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.christopherpitzer.com/&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt;, it was nice while it lasted). Its a Hanns-G HG216D no frills monitor. There was a similarly priced Acer monitor, by the Hanns-G is Energy Star which I like. It looks beautiful to me, but I have to admit the built-in 1 watt speakers are a complete joke for anything error than error beeps. Luckily they&amp;#8217;re hidden in the back of the LCD case, so no one even has to notice them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setup in Linux was as simple as pressing Ctrl-Alt-Backspace in GDM to restart X. It worked as soon as I plugged it in, but restarting X Windows auto-detected the resolution properly so I didn&amp;#8217;t have to mess around in my xorg.conf file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X Windows has come a very very long way in the past year or two. My xorg.conf file is tiny, and I&amp;#8217;m not sure why I even have it. Last time I tried, X Windows autodetected everything just fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh come on&amp;#8230; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16824254024&#34;&gt;3 days later and my monitor has already dropped $20 in price. Yeesh.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Wi-Fi in Linux? Yes, but&amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My office is upstairs, and our only cable connections are downstairs. Instead of running unsightly cables through our house or drilling holes, I just bought a Wi-Fi card for my desktop. Finding a card that works well with Linux was very very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tigerdirect.com/applications/searchtools/item-Details.asp?EdpNo=3350606&amp;amp;sku=D145-1006&#34;&gt;TP-Link TL-WN651G&lt;/a&gt; (Ver 1.5), but the box also lists the model as TL-WN650G. Most importantly it works perfectly with the [MadWiFi]&lt;a href=&#34;it uses an Atheros chipset&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;. Its running at 802.11g with WPA2. The PCI card was only $25, so I didn&amp;#8217;t even have to spend too much more for Linux compatibility. I question the reliability of those $10-$15 adapters anyway&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only caveat is caused by Debian&amp;#8217;s insistence on freeness and hatred of binary modules. The MadWiFi module uses a binary module, so Debian makes you download a source package and compile it using &lt;code&gt;module-assistant&lt;/code&gt;. Now m-a is a wonderful program, but this is still the reason I &lt;em&gt;always recommend Ubuntu to desktop users.&lt;/em&gt; Expecting anyone other than a Linux hacker to install some random package and run some random command line tool to get WiFi working is deranged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My motto: Debian is for developers, Ubuntu is for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, I&amp;#8217;ve had a wonderful day and am excited all my new toys play well with Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://madwifi.org/&#34;&gt;http://madwifi.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>