<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tomato on </title>
    <link>/tags/tomato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tomato on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/tomato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Bridges are a Scam</title>
      <link>/2007/12/18/wireless-bridges-are-a-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/12/18/wireless-bridges-are-a-scam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I am not a hardware guy. The days when I enjoyed cracking open a computer case and poking around are long since past. These days if I can&amp;#8217;t fix something via keyboard, I want no part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, for a client I needed to extend a LAN from Building A across 30 feet of asphalt to Building B. Time to don my Net Admin hat to install a nice straightforward WiFi bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite already owning a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WRT54G&#34;&gt;Linksys WRT54G series router&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to just pickup 2 Linksys &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linksys.com/servlet/Satellite?c=L_Product_C2&amp;amp;childpagename=US%2FLayout&amp;amp;cid=1134692497433&amp;amp;pagename=Linksys%2FCommon%2FVisitorWrapper&amp;amp;lid=9743339789B32&#34;&gt;WET54G&lt;/a&gt; wireless bridges (version 3.1). The &lt;strong&gt;bridges are actually &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; expensive than routers.&lt;/strong&gt; But that just means they&amp;#8217;re better suited for their simple task, right? Wrong&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 WET54Gs have been nothing but trouble for me. Their web interface sometimes redirects to the hardcoded IP address. They drop their connection and require resetting a lot. They just don&amp;#8217;t work reliably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I flashed the WRT54G with Tomato firmware to replace one of the WET54Gs, and so far things are working much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;#8217;ve never mentioned it before: &lt;strong&gt;I love &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.polarcloud.com/tomato&#34;&gt;Tomato&lt;/a&gt; firmware.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve been using it at home for ages and &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; have to reset it. The [features][4] are outstanding (QoS with ACK Prioritization is a lifesaver when working over SSH).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on anytime I need a WiFi router, access point, or bridge, I&amp;#8217;m going to buy a WRT54G and put Tomato on it. Its cheaper than buying specialized Access Points or Bridges and has lots more features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention Tomato generates sexy real-time graphs in SVG? Have a screenshot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/tomato-firmware.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/tomato-firmware.thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tomato Firmware Bandwidth Graph&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Tomato_Firmware#Features&#34;&gt;http://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Tomato_Firmware#Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>