<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fb on schmichael&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/fb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fb on schmichael&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/fb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Great article on big government</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/09/13/great-article-on-big-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/09/13/great-article-on-big-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://log.ometer.com/2009-09.html#12&#34;&gt;Havoc Pennington has a great post entitled Which Piece of Big Government Are You Against?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;War on Terror + DoD ~= 21.6% of our budget. I know we can&amp;#8217;t cut it all, but a guy can dream can&amp;#8217;t he? &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite line is in regards to how different political parties approach budgetary spending:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Republicans and Democrats judged by actions not rhetoric: government should be 105% of whatever it just was. Disagreement on where the new 5% goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So true. [Neither party has been fiscally conservative (or even responsible) for the past 30 years.][2] The Republicans just spend more on bombs while the Dems spend it on &lt;em&gt;evil&lt;/em&gt; socialist programs like welfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Emphasis added to denote sarcasm.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d much rather my tax dollars paid for some poor person&amp;#8217;s laziness (as many conservatives see welfare) than have it spent bombing the same country into oblivion twice in a bit over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is sad to see us throw away 9% of our federal budget on interest payments. Hopefully our economy will recover quickly enough for President Obama to start paying back the deficit like Clinton did in the 90s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_public_debt&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_public_debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biking to Work</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/08/07/biking-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/08/07/biking-to-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally made it up to biking to work 3 times this week! Had only been averaging about once every 2 weeks for the past couple months. Sam &amp;amp; I recently moved to North Portland which is flat. We had been living in the very hilly Southwest area of town, and biking to work from there was killer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really didn&amp;#8217;t realize how much my situation had improved until my friend, Aaron Colflesh, pointed me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heywhatsthat.com/profiler.html&#34;&gt;HeyWhatsThat.com&lt;/a&gt; which generates elevation change profiles for you based on coordinates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My current route from home to work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.schmichael.com/files/new-route.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.schmichael.com/files/new-route.png&#34; alt=&#34;current route to work&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a good 100&amp;#8242; hill in it. Not fun on the way home, but it doesn&amp;#8217;t last too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now compare that to my &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;old&lt;/em&gt; route from home to work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[![old route to work][3]][3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No wonder I never did it more than once a week! It was brutal coming home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re much happier in North Portland in general, but finding these diagrams made me feel much better about struggling to get on bike at the old place. &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: /files/old-route.png&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good-bye Lo-Fi Art, Hello YouGov</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/07/09/good-bye-lo-fi-art-hello-yougov/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/07/09/good-bye-lo-fi-art-hello-yougov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next week I&amp;#8217;ll be leaving &lt;a href=&#34;http://lofiart.com/&#34;&gt;Lo-Fi Art&lt;/a&gt; to start working for &lt;a href=&#34;http://polimetrix.com/&#34;&gt;YouGov Polimetrix&lt;/a&gt; (aka PMX). For the past couple of years I&amp;#8217;ve been consulting with Chris Pitzer mostly as a Python web developer specializing in Django. It will be sad to stop working for a company I own with a friend, but I&amp;#8217;ve been working part time for PMX and am excited to work for them full time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons for my decision, but I should make it clear that it has nothing to do with Chris! It has been great working with him, and I&amp;#8217;m glad we get to continue to share office space even if we&amp;#8217;re working on different things. There is &lt;em&gt;plenty&lt;/em&gt; of client work stacking up for him to do as well, so I&amp;#8217;m not bailing on a sinking ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So why am I leaving Lo-Fi Art?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason is probably stress. I&amp;#8217;ve just stopped enjoying client work because if I&amp;#8217;m not stressed about getting the current client done on time, I&amp;#8217;m stressed about finding the next client. If its not one of those two things, I&amp;#8217;m probably stressed about when the next check is coming in. How much was it for again? Wait, did I already get that one? Argh! On top of that I&amp;#8217;m &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; at managing money. While Chris does a great job with the company books, that doesn&amp;#8217;t keep me from screwing up my own (don&amp;#8217;t even ask me about how my tax return went this year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, contracting gigs just have a lot of &lt;strong&gt;overhead&lt;/strong&gt;. For me overhead is anything that keeps me from writing code. I really don&amp;#8217;t enjoy writing proposals and meeting with clients to discuss (or often: haggle over) implementation details. Its not that I don&amp;#8217;t like &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;. I love people! But I like working with a &lt;strong&gt;team&lt;/strong&gt; more than a &lt;strong&gt;client&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people really thrive in the consulting world. I think its just taken me years to realize I&amp;#8217;m not one of those people. I could see returning to consulting someday, but I can&amp;#8217;t imagine it would ever be back to the 2-4 week projects I currently spend most of my time on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why am I joining YouGov Polimetrix?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been a consultant for PMX working on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brandindex.com&#34;&gt;BrandIndex&lt;/a&gt; project for over a year now, and it was getting to the point where I needed to either commit or focus purely on Lo-Fi work. It was a really hard decision, but in the end PMX just gives me the opportunity to do what I love. I work in a fantastic team* with lots of fun technology in an organization that places high value on their IT resources. What more could I ask for? Oh yeah, a steady paycheck. That was a plus too. 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the dev team at PMX: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamwt.com/&#34;&gt;Jamie Turner&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/jamwt&#34;&gt;@jamwt&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://dowski.com/&#34;&gt;Christian Wyglendowski&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/dowskimania&#34;&gt;@dowskimania&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://ionrock.org/&#34;&gt;Eric Larson&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ionrock&#34;&gt;@ionrock&lt;/a&gt;), and [Robert Brewer]&lt;a href=&#34;fumanchu on irc.oftc.net&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aminus.org/blogs/index.php?blog=2&#34;&gt;http://www.aminus.org/blogs/index.php?blog=2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Server Shootout Slides</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/06/18/web-server-shootout-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/06/18/web-server-shootout-slides/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://opensourcebridge.org/sessions/119&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; has been given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides are available as &lt;a href=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/wss/wss.html&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt; or [the source OpenOffice.org Impress file][3].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who attended, and thanks to the Open Source Bridge organizers for putting on an excellent conference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;I have a bzr repository full of my log files I&amp;#8217;m considering uploading. Unfortunately the meanings of the log files are mostly in my head, so I think I should clean them up before unleashing them on the world. Ping me by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/schmichael&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:michael+blog@susens-schurter.com&#34;&gt;e-mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/wss.odp&#34;&gt;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/wss.odp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching up on photos: Lots o’ Hiking</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/04/25/catching-up-on-photos-lots-o-hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/04/25/catching-up-on-photos-lots-o-hiking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve finally gotten around to organizing and uploading over a months worth of photos off of my little digital camera. Just to make sure there&amp;#8217;s something geeky in this post: I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://f-spot.org/&#34;&gt;F-Spot&lt;/a&gt; to organize and upload my photos to PicasaWeb. Despite neither of those products being terribly popular, I really enjoy them both. I&amp;#8217;ve found PicasaWeb to be a lot easier to work with than Flickr, but Flickr definitely has a lot more support from 3rd party tools and products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/michael.schurter&#34;&gt;view all of my photo albums&lt;/a&gt; or just check out the ones you&amp;#8217;re interested in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/michael.schurter/FailedRamonaFallsHike&#34;&gt;Failed Ramona Falls Hike&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Sam &amp;amp; I attempted to hike to Ramona Falls one day, but a 6&amp;#8243; deep snow drift on &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=E+Lolo+Pass+Rd,+Hood+River,+Hood+River,+Oregon+97031&amp;amp;sll=45.480563,-122.688017&amp;amp;sspn=0.010682,0.017166&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;geocode=FZBstQId-5K9-A&amp;amp;split=0&amp;amp;ll=45.421106,-121.838379&amp;amp;spn=0.342185,0.549316&amp;amp;z=11&#34;&gt;East Lola Pass Road&lt;/a&gt; stopped us from continuing. Was still a very enjoyable day driving around Mt. Hood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/michael.schurter/HorsetailFallsHike&#34;&gt;Horsetail Falls Hike&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Fun hike in Columbia River Gorge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/michael.schurter/SaddleMountainHike&#34;&gt;Saddle Mountain Hike&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; An incredible hike that technically defeated us about a quarter of a mile before the summit. There was still a lot of snow in some spots, so we&amp;#8217;ll have to return to finish the hike someday soon!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Jen &amp;amp; Veen&amp;#8217;s visit][7] &amp;#8211; Just a random assortment of pictures from when some friends visited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[7]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/michael.schurter/JenVeenS2009Visit&#34;&gt;http://picasaweb.google.com/michael.schurter/JenVeenS2009Visit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Banks</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/03/08/bad-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2009/03/08/bad-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I try to keep up with the news, like most Americans I really have only a vague picture of this financial crisis we&amp;#8217;re in, and how to get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple pieces of media I&amp;#8217;ve found helpful in figuring out whats going on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thisamericanlife.org/Radio_Episode.aspx?episode=375&#34;&gt;This American Life did an excellent episode called Bad Banks&lt;/a&gt; which nicely explains the basic fundamentals of the banking industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week I half jokingly told friends on Thursday I expected to wake up Friday morning to find that the government had taken over the banking system. One of my friends passed on this link to an excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2009/03/06/60minutes/main4848047.shtml&#34;&gt;60 Minutes* piece on what happens when banks fail and are taken over by the FDIC&lt;/a&gt; (short story: &lt;em&gt;[Don&amp;#8217;t Panic][3]&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the best line from either of those pieces is from the This American Life episode when professor David Beim states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is not the banks, greedy though they may be, overpaid though they may be. &lt;strong&gt;The problem is us.&lt;/strong&gt; We have over-borrowed. We have been living very high on the hog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;(emphasis mine)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And now, the rest of the story&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is a blog! I can&amp;#8217;t just post some links without expounding upon my own poorly informed views! I&amp;#8217;m an American dammit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are some of my current thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;m pro stimulus package.&lt;/strong&gt; If there&amp;#8217;s ever a time for deficit spending its when the economy is in trouble and people need jobs. The &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; time for deficit spending is to destroy and then rebuild sovereign nations for no good reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I believe the government should &lt;strong&gt;Take over &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the failed banks&lt;/strong&gt;. These &lt;em&gt;too-big-to-fail&lt;/em&gt; behemoths should be taken over, parceled up, and sold off. Too-big-to-fail is unacceptable. The tax payers would probably end up paying a price for this, but consider it the &lt;strong&gt;War on Bad Banks&lt;/strong&gt;. Over the past 8 years we&amp;#8217;ve paid billions to fight a mostly phony &amp;#8220;War on Terror&amp;#8221;, why not spend billions on something that would have a positive result for humanity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the future we need regulations similar to anti-trust laws to prevent so few corporations from wielding so much power. In the computer world we turn to distributed systems to provide redundancy in case of failure. The non-geeky world has a nice little saying for this: &lt;em&gt;don&amp;#8217;t put all your eggs in one basket.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;* I hadn&amp;#8217;t seen the 60 Minutes in years. The journalist doing the story kind of annoyed me, but overall I thought it addressed something on the minds of many Americans in a very personal way.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i2.photobucket.com/albums/y34/dilliwag/panic.jpg&#34;&gt;http://i2.photobucket.com/albums/y34/dilliwag/panic.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Past 24 Hours</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/12/22/my-past-24-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/12/22/my-past-24-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, December 21st&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan is the not chance the weather and stay overnight at the airport tonight to make sure to catch our 6:30am flight Monday morning. Here&amp;#8217;s what happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00am &amp;#8211; 4:45pm &amp;#8211; Packing, checking Trimet service alerts and flight cancellations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4:45pm &amp;#8211; 6:00pm &amp;#8211; Waiting at bus stop for a bus that never came. Met a cool guy named Rob though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6:20pm &amp;#8211; Home, get call from US Airways our flight is canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6:30pm &amp;#8211; Power goes out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7:00pm &amp;#8211; 9:00pm &amp;#8211; I go on a hike. Notice my wedding ring is missing. Spend next hour hiking and digging through snow looking for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10pm &amp;#8211; Go to bed depressed, but quite warm in our sleeping bags under every blanket we own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00am &amp;#8211; Get up, still no power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:00am &amp;#8211; 12:00am &amp;#8211; Get crazy idea to try to make it to the Pitzer&amp;#8217;s in the Focus. Took 15 minutes to thaw the car and drive 15&amp;#8242; to our house. Took almost 2 hours of the greatest neighbor in the world helping put my chains back on about a dozen times just to get my car parked in front of our house.&lt;br /&gt;
Pitzer&amp;#8217;s house is not going to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1:00pm &amp;#8211; Power is back! Yay! Now we just have to figure out how to save Christmas&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part is that the PGE (utility company) truck showed up at about 11:45am at which point my car was stuck chainless in the middle of the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Anabaptist to Methodist and Back Again</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/10/19/from-anabaptist-to-methodist-and-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/10/19/from-anabaptist-to-methodist-and-back-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My wife, Samantha, and I attended &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.portlandmennonite.org/&#34;&gt;Portland Mennonite Church&lt;/a&gt; for their Sunday morning service today. The singing was beautiful.&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.portlandmennonite.org/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; The sermon excellent.&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apostolic_Christian_Church&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; And the potluck: classic.&lt;a href=&#34;http://fumcpeoria.org/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; Ironically within seconds of nervously taking a seat at potluck someone mentions going to Central Illinois for a wedding, and we discovered someone else&amp;#8217;s wife went to the same tiny summer camp in Minnesota as Sam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the real irony was in the fact that I found myself enjoying an Anabaptist service. To understand this you have to know a bit of Schurter family lore:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father grew up United Methodist, swore it off and joined a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apostolic_Christian_Church&#34;&gt;Apostolic Christian Church&lt;/a&gt;, and in the past few years has gone back to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fumcpeoria.org/&#34;&gt;United Methodist Church&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up in the Apostolic church, went off to college and became [Methodist]&lt;a href=&#34;Free, then United&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, and now I&amp;#8217;m back at an Anabaptist church (albeit Mennonite instead of German Apostolic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should clarify Sam &amp;amp; I haven&amp;#8217;t joined the Portland Mennonite Church, but we&amp;#8217;re definitely planning on going back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;1. I&amp;#8217;m a sucker for hymns and actual multi-part harmonies. This was only my second time experience Mennonite singing, but both times have been the best congregational singing I&amp;#8217;ve ever heard.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;2. It was on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parable_of_the_Talents&#34;&gt;Parable of the Talents&lt;/a&gt;. The pastor managed to speak frankly both about the current financial crisis and our responsibility to do good (the true meaning of the parable poorly summed up in a sentence fragment&amp;#8230;sorry).&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;3. Lots of casseroles (&amp;#8220;hotdish&amp;#8221; in Minnesotan).&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Protestantism#Movements_within_Protestantism&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Protestantism#Movements_within_Protestantism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>