<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flash on schmichael&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/flash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flash on schmichael&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/flash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Flash in Linux</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/09/14/adobe-flash-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/09/14/adobe-flash-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like most people, I use Flash a lot. Not only do I watch YouTube and Hulu videos, but FusionCharts* are an integral part of one of the main projects I work on. And like most people, I just want Flash to work. While an open source option would be nice, I really just need something that works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately &lt;strong&gt;Flash in Linux&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;small&gt;still&lt;/small&gt; &lt;strong&gt;sucks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, &lt;strong&gt;not for long.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flash 9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time I&amp;#8217;ve just used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://packages.debian.org/sid/flashplugin-nonfree&#34;&gt;flashplugin-nonfree&lt;/a&gt; (such an attractive package name) package to get Flash support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general this works great, unless you want to also use &lt;a href=&#34;http://pulseaudio.org/&#34;&gt;PulseAudio&lt;/a&gt;. For some reason I do, which means my audio is always out of sync. Apparently Ubuntu has a flashplugin-nonfree-pulse (another awesome package name), but &lt;a href=&#34;http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=477266#35&#34;&gt;Debian won&amp;#8217;t package it because of issues with upstream, and the fact the upcoming Flash 10 works fine without any extra wrappers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flash 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finally decide to just try out the betas of &lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.adobe.com/downloads/flashplayer10.html&#34;&gt;Flash 10&lt;/a&gt;. At this point in time, Flash 10 beta 2, is the latest, so I download it and copy the &lt;code&gt;.so&lt;/code&gt; file to &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/mozilla/plugins/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tada! Sync&amp;#8217;d audio! Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except now my browser crashes on about 1 out of every 2 sites with Flash. Some Flash doesn&amp;#8217;t render completely. Other Flash videos flicker horribly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line is even Ubuntu&amp;#8217;s notoriously unstable alpha&amp;#8217;s are better than trying to use Flash 10 beta 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Just tried Flash 10 RC 1, but its not better than beta 2. Actually it might be a bit better because it crashes &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt;, but its more frustrating in other ways: &lt;em&gt;some Flash videos don&amp;#8217;t show up at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;swfdec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing to try: &lt;a href=&#34;http://swfdec.freedesktop.org/wiki/&#34;&gt;swfdec&lt;/a&gt;, an open source Flash player. I&amp;#8217;ve followed its development closely on Planet Gnome and really respect its developer, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.gnome.org/otte/&#34;&gt;Benjamin Otte&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately it makes Flash 10 beta 2 look good by comparison. To be fair I used the unstable 0.7.4 version of swfdec, so maybe thats why it crashes fairly often. 0.8 was just released, but evidently not packaged for Debian yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll probably keep trying swfdec from time to time in the future as I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to use it, but for now I just need a Flash player that works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Gnash][7]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should try it, but the FSF can be such dicks I have a hard time even wanting to try it. They have a stupid &amp;#8220;Bad Vista&amp;#8221; logo in the upper right corner of their home page. I&amp;#8217;m no fan of Vista, but plastering the Internet with poorly drawn negative logos isn&amp;#8217;t going to win friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shouldn&amp;#8217;t let politics affect whats essentially a purely pragmatic endeavor**, so I&amp;#8217;ll probably end up trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t wait for Flash 10 to be released. While I love open source, Adobe makes excellent products, and I just need Flash to work. Its like my graphics driver: I really don&amp;#8217;t care about the source, just make my graphics work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;* Very pretty product. Decent documentation. Worthless JavaScript API and debugging features. I hope &lt;canvas&gt; becomes a viable alternative soon.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;** That endeavor being: get Flash to work as well in Linux as it does in Windows.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[7]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/gnash/&#34;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/software/gnash/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>