<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cable on schmichael&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/cable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cable on schmichael&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/cable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Dealing with Poor Customer Service</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/02/26/tips-for-dealing-with-poor-customer-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/02/26/tips-for-dealing-with-poor-customer-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/blog/2006/06/15/i-hate-sbc-and-att/#comment-26744&#34;&gt;A comment on my blog&lt;/a&gt; has inspired me to quick post a few tips I&amp;#8217;ve picked up for dealing with customer service at large companies. I&amp;#8217;m in the middle of a battle with Comcast right now because the reliability of my Internet connection is abysmal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/internet-group-chat.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chat Bubbles&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep it short.&lt;/strong&gt; Customer service/support reps are more likely to be rewarded for keeping calls short than they are for resolving customer issues. So take a tip from Republicans: work up a few brief talking points and keep driving them home until they resolve your issue.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/go-top.png&#34; alt=&#34;Go Top&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to figure out how to &lt;strong&gt;get your issue escalated.&lt;/strong&gt; In my experience there are always multiple levels of support with the first level simply reading and responding to a small number of scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found that having a detailed piece of technical information can break the scripts and get me escalated to &amp;#8220;Tier II&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Network Specialists&amp;#8221; or some other random title.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/dialog-warning.png&#34; alt=&#34;Warning Sign&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to say.&lt;/strong&gt; With ISPs don&amp;#8217;t mention VPNs, hosting services via your connection, or using 3rd party SMTP servers. While completely legitimate uses of broadband, they often fall into a broad range of &amp;#8220;unsupported&amp;#8221; uses. Worst case scenario, the rep will blame that unsupported activity for all of your issues and refuse to help you further.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/face-devilish.png&#34; alt=&#34;Devil Face&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know when to &lt;em&gt;lie&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is closely related to the previous point. I use Linux, but I always say I use Windows. ISPs often only support &lt;em&gt;a single computer directly connected to your broadband modem&lt;/em&gt;. Just lie, but make sure you have access to any administrative interface your modem might have.*&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/face-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Smiling Face&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be friendly, chances are they hate their job.&lt;/strong&gt; This can be tough to do especially when the poor rep just wants to get rid of you ASAP so he/she can go on break. I&amp;#8217;ve found making little self-deprecating jokes about being a &amp;#8220;pain in the ass customer&amp;#8221; or asking permission to lie when asked those stupid questions like &amp;#8220;have you tried rebooting?&amp;#8221;. This tip may help you get escalated as well.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/face-sad.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sad Face&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be careful when bluffing.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve threatened to quit a service before only to have the rep say &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m sorry to here that sir, have a nice day.&amp;#8221; I don&amp;#8217;t even think she was cleverly calling my bluff; she just saw the opportunity to end the call! If you&amp;#8217;re going to make a threat make it something that actually makes life difficult for them like talking to their manager or getting a full refund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, try the friendly approach first. Remember you&amp;#8217;re talking to real people who probably hate the company your dealing with more than you!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/network-error.png&#34; alt=&#34;Network Error&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, don&amp;#8217;t forget: &lt;em&gt;it could be your fault.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Reset your modem. Reset your router. Actually try Internet Explorer instead of Firefox when they ask you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best example of this is when I pestered a poor customer rep for 15 minutes trying to figure out and then reset my password only to find out I needed to type a full e-mail address as the username instead of just the username part. I had the correct password all along. Luckily the rep was very nice about it.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My cable modem&amp;#8217;s administrative interface is accessible at [192.168.100.1][2] which seems standard for cable modems. My home network&amp;#8217;s subnet is 192.168.1.1, so my router happily just treats my modem like any other Internet site. This is a great way to be able to &amp;#8220;prove&amp;#8221; to reps that you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;directly connected&amp;#8221; to your modem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.100.1&#34;&gt;http://192.168.100.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Cable Internet, 22″ LCD, and WiFi!</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2007/12/17/new-cable-internet-22-lcd-and-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2007/12/17/new-cable-internet-22-lcd-and-wifi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was my work Christmas! I work from home most of the time, so I&amp;#8217;m finally getting around to upgrading some of the equipment I use for my job every day. Today I got 3 new pieces of technology and just finished setting them all up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goodbye ATT&amp;amp;T!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched from 1.5 Mbps/386 Kbps DSL to 10 Mbps/1 Mbps cable broadband today. I used to download packages at 140 KBps to 160 KBps, but now I easily reach over 1 MBps. Tomorrow I get to call AT&amp;amp;T and cancel not only my DSL but also my landline phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only downside is starting in 2008, my local cable company, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insight-com.com/&#34;&gt;Insight&lt;/a&gt;, is going to become &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comcast.com/&#34;&gt;Comcast&lt;/a&gt;. It took me about 10 seconds to get a human on the line when calling Insight. When I tried to call Comcast to find out if anything was going to change, I had to call &lt;em&gt;3 different phone numbers&lt;/em&gt; until I finally reached a sales person who kept trying to sell me a package deal for broadband/tv/phone even though Comcast isn&amp;#8217;t in my area yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales representatives for both companies seemed very confused that a person would only want Internet access. My wife &amp;amp; I watch all of our TV online or through Netflix, and we don&amp;#8217;t need a landline phone. Is that really so strange these days? I suppose most people still have cable TV or satellite, but with more shows becoming available for free online I don&amp;#8217;t see the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello 22&amp;#8243; LCD!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got a nice LCD and got rid of my $5 19&amp;#8243; inch CRT (thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.christopherpitzer.com/&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt;, it was nice while it lasted). Its a Hanns-G HG216D no frills monitor. There was a similarly priced Acer monitor, by the Hanns-G is Energy Star which I like. It looks beautiful to me, but I have to admit the built-in 1 watt speakers are a complete joke for anything error than error beeps. Luckily they&amp;#8217;re hidden in the back of the LCD case, so no one even has to notice them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setup in Linux was as simple as pressing Ctrl-Alt-Backspace in GDM to restart X. It worked as soon as I plugged it in, but restarting X Windows auto-detected the resolution properly so I didn&amp;#8217;t have to mess around in my xorg.conf file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X Windows has come a very very long way in the past year or two. My xorg.conf file is tiny, and I&amp;#8217;m not sure why I even have it. Last time I tried, X Windows autodetected everything just fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh come on&amp;#8230; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16824254024&#34;&gt;3 days later and my monitor has already dropped $20 in price. Yeesh.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Wi-Fi in Linux? Yes, but&amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My office is upstairs, and our only cable connections are downstairs. Instead of running unsightly cables through our house or drilling holes, I just bought a Wi-Fi card for my desktop. Finding a card that works well with Linux was very very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tigerdirect.com/applications/searchtools/item-Details.asp?EdpNo=3350606&amp;amp;sku=D145-1006&#34;&gt;TP-Link TL-WN651G&lt;/a&gt; (Ver 1.5), but the box also lists the model as TL-WN650G. Most importantly it works perfectly with the [MadWiFi]&lt;a href=&#34;it uses an Atheros chipset&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;. Its running at 802.11g with WPA2. The PCI card was only $25, so I didn&amp;#8217;t even have to spend too much more for Linux compatibility. I question the reliability of those $10-$15 adapters anyway&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only caveat is caused by Debian&amp;#8217;s insistence on freeness and hatred of binary modules. The MadWiFi module uses a binary module, so Debian makes you download a source package and compile it using &lt;code&gt;module-assistant&lt;/code&gt;. Now m-a is a wonderful program, but this is still the reason I &lt;em&gt;always recommend Ubuntu to desktop users.&lt;/em&gt; Expecting anyone other than a Linux hacker to install some random package and run some random command line tool to get WiFi working is deranged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My motto: Debian is for developers, Ubuntu is for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, I&amp;#8217;ve had a wonderful day and am excited all my new toys play well with Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://madwifi.org/&#34;&gt;http://madwifi.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>