<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Purgatory on schmichael&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/purgatory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Purgatory on schmichael&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.schmichael.com/tags/purgatory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Dealing with Poor Customer Service</title>
      <link>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/02/26/tips-for-dealing-with-poor-customer-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.schmichael.com/2008/02/26/tips-for-dealing-with-poor-customer-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/blog/2006/06/15/i-hate-sbc-and-att/#comment-26744&#34;&gt;A comment on my blog&lt;/a&gt; has inspired me to quick post a few tips I&amp;#8217;ve picked up for dealing with customer service at large companies. I&amp;#8217;m in the middle of a battle with Comcast right now because the reliability of my Internet connection is abysmal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/internet-group-chat.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chat Bubbles&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep it short.&lt;/strong&gt; Customer service/support reps are more likely to be rewarded for keeping calls short than they are for resolving customer issues. So take a tip from Republicans: work up a few brief talking points and keep driving them home until they resolve your issue.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/go-top.png&#34; alt=&#34;Go Top&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to figure out how to &lt;strong&gt;get your issue escalated.&lt;/strong&gt; In my experience there are always multiple levels of support with the first level simply reading and responding to a small number of scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found that having a detailed piece of technical information can break the scripts and get me escalated to &amp;#8220;Tier II&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Network Specialists&amp;#8221; or some other random title.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/dialog-warning.png&#34; alt=&#34;Warning Sign&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to say.&lt;/strong&gt; With ISPs don&amp;#8217;t mention VPNs, hosting services via your connection, or using 3rd party SMTP servers. While completely legitimate uses of broadband, they often fall into a broad range of &amp;#8220;unsupported&amp;#8221; uses. Worst case scenario, the rep will blame that unsupported activity for all of your issues and refuse to help you further.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/face-devilish.png&#34; alt=&#34;Devil Face&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know when to &lt;em&gt;lie&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is closely related to the previous point. I use Linux, but I always say I use Windows. ISPs often only support &lt;em&gt;a single computer directly connected to your broadband modem&lt;/em&gt;. Just lie, but make sure you have access to any administrative interface your modem might have.*&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/face-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Smiling Face&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be friendly, chances are they hate their job.&lt;/strong&gt; This can be tough to do especially when the poor rep just wants to get rid of you ASAP so he/she can go on break. I&amp;#8217;ve found making little self-deprecating jokes about being a &amp;#8220;pain in the ass customer&amp;#8221; or asking permission to lie when asked those stupid questions like &amp;#8220;have you tried rebooting?&amp;#8221;. This tip may help you get escalated as well.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/face-sad.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sad Face&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be careful when bluffing.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve threatened to quit a service before only to have the rep say &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m sorry to here that sir, have a nice day.&amp;#8221; I don&amp;#8217;t even think she was cleverly calling my bluff; she just saw the opportunity to end the call! If you&amp;#8217;re going to make a threat make it something that actually makes life difficult for them like talking to their manager or getting a full refund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, try the friendly approach first. Remember you&amp;#8217;re talking to real people who probably hate the company your dealing with more than you!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;float:left;padding:0px 3px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://michael.susens-schurter.com/files/network-error.png&#34; alt=&#34;Network Error&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, don&amp;#8217;t forget: &lt;em&gt;it could be your fault.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Reset your modem. Reset your router. Actually try Internet Explorer instead of Firefox when they ask you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best example of this is when I pestered a poor customer rep for 15 minutes trying to figure out and then reset my password only to find out I needed to type a full e-mail address as the username instead of just the username part. I had the correct password all along. Luckily the rep was very nice about it.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My cable modem&amp;#8217;s administrative interface is accessible at [192.168.100.1][2] which seems standard for cable modems. My home network&amp;#8217;s subnet is 192.168.1.1, so my router happily just treats my modem like any other Internet site. This is a great way to be able to &amp;#8220;prove&amp;#8221; to reps that you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;directly connected&amp;#8221; to your modem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.100.1&#34;&gt;http://192.168.100.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>